[
  {
    "question": "Which statement is an advantage of the platform as a service (PaaS) cloud service model?",
    "options": [
      "PaaS provides the greatest level of control over IT resources.",
      "PaaS reduces the need to handle application deployments.",
      "PaaS is the most similar to traditional on-premises models for IT resources.",
      "PaaS avoids the need to manage operating systems."
    ],
    "correctIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "How does cloud computing improve a company's ability to provision resources to meet capacity demands compared to on-premises computing?",
    "options": [
      "Cloud resources can be cost forecasted.",
      "Cloud resources can be locked down to the resource level.",
      "Cloud resources can scale up or down based on demand.",
      "Cloud resources can experience peaks and valleys in usage."
    ],
    "correctIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statements about how a company would use AWS Organizations are accurate? (Select TWO.)",
    "options": [
      "A company can use AWS Organizations to create security groups that control access to resources.",
      "A company can only manage AWS Organizations through the AWS Management Console.",
      "A company can use AWS Organizations' consolidated identity and access management (IAM) feature to replace the existing IAM system for an individual account.",
      "A company can consolidate and centrally manage multiple AWS accounts.",
      "A company can benefit from volume discounts with consolidated billing."
    ],
    "correctIndex": [
      3,
      4
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A cloud practitioner wants to visualize their AWS costs per EC2 instance type for the past 3 months. Which AWS tool or feature should they use?",
    "options": [
      "AWS Pricing Calculator",
      "AWS Cost Explorer",
      "AWS Budgets",
      "AWS Bills page"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about AWS Regions is true?",
    "options": [
      "All AWS accounts can access all AWS Regions.",
      "Data stored in an AWS Region isn't subject to geographical compliance requirements.",
      "Using a Region as close as possible to users can reduce latency.",
      "All available Regions are enabled by default in an AWS account."
    ],
    "correctIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statements about AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) policies are accurate? (Select TWO.)",
    "options": [
      "Access control lists (ACLs) are a form of resource-based policies.",
      "Identity-based policies are attached to a user, group, or role.",
      "Identity-based policies can only be attached to a single entity.",
      "Resource-based policies are attached to a user, group, or role.",
      "Resource-based policies allow access by default."
    ],
    "correctIndex": [
      0,
      1
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A company must produce reports of any changes to its Amazon EC2 instance settings. Which AWS service should they use?",
    "options": [
      "AWS Artifact",
      "Amazon CloudWatch",
      "AWS CloudTrail",
      "AWS Config"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "A network administrator wants to run their ecommerce web application on a virtual private cloud (VPC). Which step is part of setting up the VPC? (Select TWO.)",
    "options": [
      "Specify the range of IP addresses for the VPC.",
      "Delete the local route in the route table.",
      "Create the main route table.",
      "Attach the VPC to a security group.",
      "Create private and public subnets."
    ],
    "correctIndex": [
      0,
      4
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which requirement suggests configuring Amazon Route 53 with latency routing?",
    "options": [
      "A company wants to detect website outages and automatically redirect customers to a healthy location.",
      "A company wants to route traffic to the Region that provides the fastest experience based on performance measurements.",
      "A company wants to perform A/B testing and route traffic to different locations based on a percentage of traffic.",
      "A company wants to route traffic to only locations where they have distribution rights."
    ],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "A company wants complete control over its server's configurations, operating system (OS), and application software stack. Which AWS compute service should they choose?",
    "options": [
      "AWS Lambda",
      "Amazon EC2",
      "Amazon RDS",
      "Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS)"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "A developer needs temporary block storage for cache data on an Amazon EC2 instance. Which option should they choose?",
    "options": [
      "Amazon S3",
      "Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS)",
      "Amazon EC2 instance store",
      "Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS)"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "A developer wants to use Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS) for their application. What action should they take?",
    "options": [
      "Attach the Amazon EBS volume to an Amazon EC2 instance.",
      "Back up the Amazon EBS volume using Snapshots.",
      "Replicate the Amazon EBS volume in a different Availability Zone.",
      "Attach the Amazon EBS volume to multiple Amazon EC2 instances in multiple Availability Zones."
    ],
    "correctIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "A company needs to store long-lived data. They need the data to be available immediately, but access patterns are unpredictable. Which Amazon S3 storage class would be most cost-effective?",
    "options": [
      "Amazon S3 Standard",
      "Amazon S3 One Zone-Infrequent Access",
      "Amazon S3 Glacier",
      "Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which scenario describes a good use case for Amazon S3 Standard storage?",
    "options": [
      "Running a relational database",
      "Hosting website images",
      "Sharing an NFS file system",
      "Act as an EC2 instance store."
    ],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which option is a company's responsibility when running Amazon RDS?",
    "options": [
      "Application optimization",
      "Operating system patching",
      "Database software patching",
      "Operating system installation"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an attribute in an Amazon DynamoDB table?",
    "options": [
      "A data element that is shared by all items in a table",
      "A key that uniquely identifies a set of data elements",
      "A data element that doesn't need to be broken down further",
      "A set of related data"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement reflects a design principle of the Security pillar of the AWS Well-Architected Framework?",
    "options": [
      "Ensure that staff are actively monitoring potential risks manually.",
      "Apply security at all layers of an architecture.",
      "Decentralize permissions management.",
      "Don't deploy a solution to production until you're certain that there are no security risks."
    ],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of alert might be provided by AWS Trusted Advisor?",
    "options": [
      "An alert of unusual API calls made in an AWS account",
      "An alert that multi-factor authentication (MFA) isn't activated on an AWS account",
      "An alert that an AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) user has requested service quota changes",
      "An alert of unauthorized access in an AWS account"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "A company has an application running on two Amazon EC2 instances. They want to reduce idle EC2 capacity. The application load is difficult to forecast, and they want to keep the CPU utilization close to 40 percent on all instances. Which type of Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling should they configure?",
    "options": [
      "Scheduled scaling",
      "Manual scaling",
      "Predictive scaling",
      "Dynamic scaling"
    ],
    "correctIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Elastic Load Balancing (ELB) used with Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling? (Select TWO).",
    "options": [
      "ELB triggers an Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling event when a threshold is reached.",
      "ELB performs health checks on new Amazon EC2 instances that are added to the Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling group.",
      "ELB establishes the minimum and maximum number of instances in the Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling group.",
      "ELB automatically adds new instances to the Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling group when the load reaches a predetermined limit.",
      "ELB distributes traffic between Amazon EC2 instances in an Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling group."
    ],
    "correctIndex": [
      1,
      4
    ]
  }
]